### **Terence Ke Wen CHOK**

Mobile: +65 9123 4567

Email: <a href="mailto:terence.chok@nus.edu.sg">terence.chok@nus.edu.sg</a></a></a>Skype: <a href="mailto:chok@nus.edu.sg">chalkterence@gmail.com</a>

Linkedin: https://sg.linkedin.com/in/terchok

Github: https://github.com/terchalk



#### **Personal Statement**

#### **About Me**

I am a Year 3 undergraduate from National University of Singapore pursuing an honors degree in Computer Science with specialization in Visual Computing. I am an inquisitive person who likes learning and adapting to situations. I thoroughly enjoy playing competitive video games as my hobby because it requires productive communication and focus.

## **Internship Objectives**

I hope to gain valuable working experience in the Information Technology (IT) industry at Silicon Valley, a place that is vibrant in the tech scene. In addition, I would like to expand my network and be exposed to the overseas start-up ecosystem.

### **Work Experience**

During my summer break two summers ago, (May to Aug 2015), my friend and I made a game that involved platform jumping and bullet dodging. The purpose of the project was to get first-hand experience in game development while fulfilling our summer project requirement. I picked up new skills quickly like user testing, stage design and music composition during the process. The project was a success and we received the Apollo 11 Award for the summer program. Our game can be downloaded at <a href="https://github.com/Vylantze/Chaos-Children">https://github.com/Vylantze/Chaos-Children</a>.

Last summer, I was a software engineering intern at SOZOCO. SOZOCO is a start-up company that specializes in creating custom-made nail polish through their mobile application, NailDeck. A user would take a photograph, select a specific color on the photo and the application would send the selected color to the nail polish makers. As part of the technical team, I was tasked to create the Android version of NailDeck from scratch. (it is an iOS application) During the development, I had to quickly pick up new skills as mobile application development is a field which I had no prior experience in. I managed to implement all the core functionalities that the application would need to be useful before my internship ended.

In my third year of university education, I was a teaching assistant for CS1010, Programming Methodology. It is a basic programming module designed for freshmen who has little to no programming background. As a teaching assistant, my responsibilities include conducting discussion classes, grading lab and practical assignments. The main challenge is to simplify programming concepts so that students are able to understand the programming concepts better.

### Strengths & Weaknesses

I am a self-motivated person. Despite not having any mobile development experience, I took the time to take up Android Development courses so that I am better equipped for my internship. I am also taking web development courses to increase my exposure as an aspiring software developer.

I am also a team player. I understand the importance of working with others to achieve a common goal and the need to be flexible in taking up responsibilities in a team setting.

However, there were times where I am reluctant in asking for help from my colleagues because I was afraid of being a liability. This proved to be a hindrance when I am doing my internship in a start-up, where deadlines of deliverables are very crucial. Under the guidance of my supervisors, I changed my mindset and seek assistance from people with more experience, so that I can keep up with the team.

#### **How I Can Contribute**

My interests lie with web application development, both front-end and back-end. I do understand that the need of every startup varies and thus, I am willing to adapt to any changing needs of your company so that I can be a valuable asset. My personal goal would be to make a positive difference through my responsibilities.

#### Education

| Aug 2014 – Present  | National University of Singapore Bachelor of Computing (Honours) in Computer Science (Course Details in Appendix A)  | Singapore |
|---------------------|--|-----------|
| Jan 2010 - Dec 2012 | Serangoon Junior College<br>Singapore-Cambridge General Certification of Education, Advanced<br>Level  | Singapore |
| Work Experience     |  |           |
| Aug 2016 - Present  | <ul> <li>National University of Singapore Teaching Assistant</li> <li>Conducts discussion sessions and grades assignments</li> <li>Conducts extra lessons for students who are facing difficulties</li> </ul>  | Singapore |
| May 2016 - Aug 2016 | <ul> <li>SoZOCO Software Engineering Intern</li> <li>Headed the development of NailDeck, Android</li> <li>Implemented core functionalities of the e-commerce application</li> <li>Proposed a pipeline of features for future improvements</li> </ul> | Singapore |
| May 2012 – May 2014 | Singapore Armed Forces Communications IC  Managed the signal operations and equipment allocation   | Singapore |

# Scholastic Achievements/Extracurricular Activities

| Aug 2015            | Smart Port Hackathon by Maritime and Port Authority of Singapore  1st Prize (Student Category)   | Singapore |
|---------------------|--|-----------|
| Aug 2015 - Oct 2016 | <ul> <li>National University of Singapore, School of Computing</li> <li>Welfare Director for NUS Students' Computing Club</li> <li>Organizing Committee for Computing Day 2016</li> </ul>  | Singapore |
| May 2015 – Aug 2015 | <ul> <li>Orbital Summer Program, School of Computing</li> <li>Recipient of Apollo 11 (Advanced) award</li> </ul>   | Singapore |
| Jan 2010 - Dec 2012 | <ul> <li>Serangoon Junior College</li> <li>Member of Serangoon Junior College Symphonic Band</li> <li>Singapore Youth Festival 2011 Central Judging – Recipient of Bronze Award</li> </ul> | Singapore |

Supervised the supply operations for combined military exercises

# **Skill Sets & Proficiency**

Office Productivity Microsoft Word **Proficient** 

Microsoft PowerPoint Intermediate Microsoft Excel Intermediate

Multimedia Adobe Photoshop CS5 Intermediate

> Wondershare Video Editor Basic

Web HTML, CSS Intermediate

> **Javascript Basic** PHP Basic NodeJS, JQuery Basic React **Basic**

Mobile Android Development Intermediate

**Programming** Java Intermediate

С Intermediate C++ Basic C# Basic **Firebase** Basic OpenGL Basic **OpenCV** Basic Python **Basic** 

**Integrated Development** Unity3D

Basic **Environments Eclipse** Basic

**Android Studios** Intermediate

**IDLE Basic** 

Markup **XML** Basic

**Operating Systems** Windows 7, 10 Basic

> Unix **Basic**

**Collaborative and Task** 

**Management Tools** Google Docs Intermediate

Slack Intermediate

Intermediate

**Version Control Systems** Basic Git

Github Basic

**BitBucket** Intermediate

## Language Proficiency

**Spoken** English - fluent; Mandarin - fluent Written English - competent; Chinese - average

Trello

#### **Additional Information**

Other activities/interests: Music Production, Guitar, Drums, Percussions.

Degree: Bachelor of Computing (Honours) in Computer Science

| Year           | Level             | Course Description                                  | Module Type |
|----------------|-------------------|---|-------------|
| Aug – Nov 2014 | Year 1/Semester 1 | Programming Methodology                             | Essential   |
|                |                   | Discrete Structures                                 | Essential   |
|                |                   | Calculus in Computing                               | Elective    |
|                |                   | US: From Settlement to Superpower                   | Elective    |
|                |                   | Linear Algebra I                                    | Elective    |
| Jan – May 2015 | Year 1/Semester 2 | Data Structures and Algorithms I                    | Essential   |
|                |                   | Computer Organization                               | Essential   |
|                |                   | Probability and Statistics                          | Essential   |
|                |                   | Genes and Society                                   | Elective    |
|                |                   | Orbital Project                                     | Essential   |
| Aug – Nov 2015 | Year 2/Semester 1 | Data Structures and Algorithms II                   | Essential   |
|                |                   | Software Engineering                                | Essential   |
|                |                   | Effective Communication for Computing Professionals | Essential   |
|                |                   | Critical Thinking in the Information Age            | Essential   |
|                |                   | Computing and Society                               | Essential   |
| Jan – May 2016 | Year 2/Semester 2 | Introduction to Operating Systems                   | Essential   |
|                |                   | Computer Graphics                                   | Essential   |
|                |                   | Multivariable Calculus                              | Elective    |
|                |                   | Animal Behaviour                                    | Elective    |
|                |                   | Design and Analysis of Algorithms                   | Essential   |
| Aug – Nov 2016 | Year 3/Semester 1 | Introduction to Computer Networking                 | Essential   |
|                |                   | General Biology                                     | Elective    |
|                |                   | Computer Vision                                     | Essential   |
|                |                   | Machine Learning                                    | Essential   |
|                |                   | Singapore Film: Performance of Identity             | Elective    |